...your prize, a brand new car.
Susan, are you ready?
Calm down, Susan.
Susan Alexander...
You? What--? What did--?
Help.
Help me.
Call the paramedics.
I'll get the nurse.
Marcus, help Ruth.
Kathy.
What are you doing
leaving my brother alone?
We lost him.
No.
He's gone.
- What's happened?
- My brother's dead.
- They think he had a heart attack.
- Oh, no.
You were supposed to be
on duty tonight.
If you'd been here
when he needed you,
Peter would still be alive.
But he told me to go,
he said it was all right.
I will have your things sent to you.
- I loved him.
- You get out of here.
Now.
Miss St. John?
There's something bothering me.
Just before your brother rang,
yelling for help,
I looked out the window.
I saw her coming into the house.
She was in the house?
When my brother died?
Thank you, Marcus. Just one more
and I think we'll be finished.
Hold the elevator, please.
Thank you. Excuse me.
- Oh, are you--? Are you all right?
- I'm fine. Are you?
Excuse me.
I think we'd better call for help.
If anybody's here,
I'm sure they've heard that.
How long do you think it'll take
to get us out?
I don't know, but how about:
There.
I'm not claustrophobic,
it's just that today's
the first day on a new job
- and I don't wanna be late.
- Oh, I don't blame you.
You're not from around here,
are you?
No.
I didn't think
I heard grits in your voice.
No.
- Midwest?
- Yes.
- Iowa?
- Nebraska.
- Close.
- Close, yes.
Well, there you go.
Smooth as a cow on ice.
Well, nice riding with you.
Yeah. Yeah.
How can they say I killed Peter?
I loved him.
The state prison over in Jackson
is full of loving killers.
The night Peter died,
I was with somebody.
Who is this person?
Mr. Matlock, I know about
your hundred-thousand-dollar fee,
and I can afford it.
Nursing pays well, doesn't it?
Here's proof that I didn't kill Peter.
It's an engagement ring he gave me.
He told me it's worth at least
a quarter of a million dollars.
And why would I kill him
if we were getting married?
I'm trying to decide
whether or not to take your case.
To do that,
I have to know everything you know.
Who were you with
the night of the murder?
My husband.
When your fianc was murdered,
you were with your husband?
We're getting divorced.
The only reason I left Peter
was because Eric called, very angry,
wanting to talk,
and Peter told me to...
Mr. Matlock, please.
I guess I can always use
another ring.
Case number A-98304,
The State v. Kathy Dawson.
Ben Matlock for the defence,
Your Honour.
Where's the prosecutor?
Your Honour,
I apologise for being late,
but I was unavoidably detained.
Julie March, assistant district attorney
for the state.
Hello.
The radiator hose on my car just...
- I didn't know that--
- I didn't know that you were--
- Yeah.
- Well, how could we know?
- I mean--
- Yeah, that's right.
- Good luck.
- Oh, thank you. Good luck to you too.
Let's get on to the plea
and arraignment.
Your Honour, the defendant
has been advised of her rights,
waives reading of the indictment,
pleads not guilty, waives time.
Well,
first available slot
is a week from next Tuesday.
That time is acceptable to the state,
Your Honour.
Fine by me, Your Honour.
Defence also requests
that bail be waived
and the defendant be released
on her own recognizance.
Your Honour, this is a capital case.
The defendant has
no priors whatsoever, Your Honour,
not even a traffic ticket.
Your Honour,
her driving is not the issue.
My client is a lifelong resident
of this city, gainfully employed.
And it is through her employment
as a nurse
that the state contends
she brutally murdered the decedent.
The prosecution's evidence
is purely circumstantial,
and we have no reason to believe
my client will leave the jurisdiction.
- Which we seriously question.
- Counsel.
You will direct your arguments
to the court and not to one another.
This is not a free-for-all.
Bail is denied at this time.
Thank you, counsel.
Thank you, Your Honour.
I'm sorry.
I'll be all right.
Case number A-96407,
The State v. Arnold Passer.
Excuse me, excuse me.
- You're very good.
- Why, thank you. So are you.
Peter St. John was one of
the richest men in the new South,
worth maybe
a hundred million dollars.
Why do you suppose
somebody gonna marry into that
would wanna kill him?
Motive?
He was going to marry her?
- Oh, please, please.
- All right.
There...
...is a $250,000 engagement ring.
Well, I'll grant you
I can't supply motive,
but I sure have everything else.
Oh, and it looks to me
like you've got yourself
one hell of a retainer.
Hello, my baby
Hello, my honey
Hello, my ragtime gal
Send me a kiss by wire
Baby, my heart's on fire
If you refuse me
Baby, you'll lose me
Then you'll be all alone
So, baby, telephone
And tell me I'm your own
- Good morning, everybody.
- Good morning.
How is everything
on the Russell matter?
I'm only one good precedent away
from winning an appeal.
Good.
Charlene,
I want you to tell me something.
I will. You left your wallet
on your desk again.
Take a good objective look at me.
Why are you smiling like that?
Pretend you don't know me.
Tell me how old you think I am.
Be honest.
- I know how old you are.
- Well, I don't, and I'd say pretty old.
And in that suit, very old.
Here's Eric Dawson's address.
That's Kathy's husband.
He works at a garage
on Tenth Street.
She said she was with him
the night of the murder.
And am I to assume
by this vote of confidence
that the police can't find him?
Ben, I'm flattered.
- I'll see y'all.
- Excuse me. Ben Matlock?
The young man over there.
- Good morning, Mr. Matlock.
- What's this?
I'm sorry, but the St. John family
reported a theft
on the night of the murder.
This is a search warrant
for certain described personal property.
What property?
A lady's large
diamond engagement ring.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
There's a new assistant DA in town.
Very efficient.
- Yes?
- I'm Ben Matlock,
- Kathy Dawson's lawyer.
- We have nothing to say to you.
- What is it, Lacey?
- It's her lawyer.
- May I look around the house?
- Can he do that?
Yes, he can.
Can you arrange
to get my mother's ring back?
The police are holding it as evidence.
My mother gave that ring to me,
and your client stole it out of my room
the day she murdered my brother.
- That's enough.
- I want my ring back,
and I want your client
to pay for killing my brother.
Come in, Mr. Matlock.
Mr. Matlock, I'm Barbara Warren.
I believe you knew my father, Bob.
- Oh, yes. A fine lawyer.
- Thank you.
Could I see Mr. St. John's room?
Of course. It's upstairs.
So...Peter St. John.
From near poverty to
one of the richest men in the country.
- That's success.
- Yes, he was quite talented,
and he handled it well.
I didn't actually know him.
I met him once.
Your father represented him,
didn't he?
Oh, yes, nearly from the first deal.
They were great friends,
and you know, Peter didn't have many.
After your father died,
did the firm handle his business?
Yes, of course. Why do you ask?
I just heard
that some of the bigger clients
sought other representation,
and I'm glad that Peter St. John
stayed with you.
- Must be a full-time job in itself.
- Oh, yes it is.
That's why I'm here now, to help Lacey
kind of sort out of the estate.
What did you think
of Kathy Dawson?
She was capable, very professional.
Of course, she left Peter alone
when we were doing business,
so it's very hard for me to say.
Did you get any sense
of a romance?
The whole time
that I was visiting with Peter,
he never gave any indication
that they had anything
but a professional relationship.
That was Peter's room.
I'll be in the library
if you need anything.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Put that down at once.
You must have cat's feet.
I thought I was by myself.
I'm Ben Matlock, Kathy's lawyer.
I'm Ruth Delaney, the housekeeper.
It's my job to be unobtrusive,
unlike some people.
That's a pretty lady. Who is she?
Mr. St. John's wife.
She died four years ago Christmas.
How long did you work for her?
Her family's employed me for years.
When she married Mr. St. John,
I came with her
to help her run this house.
- Pretty worldly woman.
- Yes.
Kathy isn't at all.
That nurse is a little tramp.
- Isn't that kind of hard?
- Hard?
All she could think about
from the instant she walked in
the front door was money.
Mr. St. John was a great man,
and she killed him.
He just waltzed in here as pretty as
could be yesterday morning and quit.
No notice, nothing.
- He didn't say where he was going?
- Not a word, just took his pay and left.
Come on, he had to give you some
kind of idea, like he was leaving town?
Man, I was so teed off at Eric
for quitting like that,
I kicked his butt out before
he had a chance to say anything.
Well, you know, that's
an understandable reaction, Mark.
Tell you what,
if you think of something,
give me a call.
Might be some money in it, huh?
You're a shrewd businessman,
what do you think?
Lacey's lying.
Peter gave me that ring.
She said it was in her room
and you took it.
It was in the safe in the library.
The bookcase opposite
from the fireplace opens up
- and behind it is a safe.
- Let me get this straight.
He sent you downstairs and told you
to bring the ring up to him.
First, he gave me the combination,
and yes, he did.
Who else had this combination?
Nobody. Only Peter.
So all of a sudden, one day,
he just gives you
the secret combination?
Peter insisted
that I have this particular ring,
so he sent me to the safe to get it.
Kathy,
a man as rich as Peter St. John
could have a dozen rings
sent over to him and just pick one.
I'm just asking all the questions
the jury's gonna ask.
I didn't want that ring.
I wanted one of my own
that we picked out together,
but Peter insisted.
What else could I have done?
The registration
in the glove compartment
says this car belongs
to Eric Dawson.
Now, are you Eric,
or is this grand theft auto in progress?
No, this is my car.
What the hell are you doing in it?
Then this is for you.
It's a subpoena to your wife's trial.
Felon.
Julie, don't do that to a person.
So it's Julie now.
Are we friends,
or are you just being charming
because I caught you in the act
and you're afraid
I'll make a citizen's arrest?
Kathy gave me the combination.
Peter St. John sent her down here,
told her to open the safe,
bring the ring up to him.
Nobody else had the combination.
If it works, I think she's telling the truth
about the ring.
All right.
- Seven left, 30 right--
- No, not so fast.
And 20 left.
Thirty.
Okay.
There you go.
- Want a look?
- Yes.
This looks like an inventory.
Emerald earrings, matching necklace,
matching ring.
- Two million dollars.
- Way overpriced.
A million-five, tops.
- Are you some kind of expert?
- I'd do a lot better if I had my loupe.
Good Lord, these are cultured.
Let's see.
Ruby earrings, diamond necklace,
diamond-- Oh, here.
Well, that's interesting.
The diamond necklace is missing.
And here's the ring.
Diamond solitaire, emerald cut,
a quarter of a million dollars.
And here is the ring box.
Empty.
- You know what I think?
- You think I lied.
- You did, didn't you?
- Yes.
I'm not particularly proud of the fact,
but yes, I lied.
Why?
Because I know
she killed my brother.
I want her convicted.
Show Mr. Matlock
and Miss March out.
Yes, ma'am.
Do I understand correctly
you are from the office
of the district attorney?
Yes.
This was sealed
when Mr. St. John gave it to me.
He said it was important
and confidential,
and I suppose
the state should have it now.
It's a handwritten will.
He left everything to Kathy?
About $1 50 million.
No further questions, Your Honour.
Mr. Scott, you testified
you saw my client go into the house
a few minutes
before Mr. St. John died.
- Is that correct?
- Yes, sir.
And you were in your apartment
by the kitchen looking out the window.
Is that correct?
I saw someone come up the driveway
and enter the house.
- It was pretty dark, wasn't it?
- Yes.
You know, I went to your place,
turned on the television,
and I looked out the window.
You know what I saw?
Objection.
Mr. Matlock is not testifying here,
but if he would like to be sworn,
I'll be happy to cross-examine him.
Sustained.
Counsel will confine himself
to questioning the witness.
Mr. Scott,
you saw the outline of a woman
wearing a raincoat and a scarf similar
to the ones owned by Miss Dawson,
so you assumed the outline you saw
was Miss Dawson, correct?
Objection. Vague and ambiguous,
argumentative, compound,
asked and answered.
If counsel will allow me to continue,
maybe we can get to the truth
with this witness.
I admonish you both again
that you will direct your comments
to the court and not to one another.
Objection sustained.
Rephrase the question.
You assumed it was Miss Dawson,
didn't you?
No, sir. I know it was.
But the person was covered
with a raincoat and a scarf.
Yes, but she also had the walk.
I've been paying attention to the way
women walk since I was 4 years old.
- Kathy had--
- Mr. Scott, just answer yes or no.
- Objection.
- No further questions.
- Redirect?
- No, thank you, Your Honour.
This court is adjourned
till 9 a.m. tomorrow morning.
I suggest counsel
cool their tempers by that time
as the court is seriously considering
contempt citations against both of you.
Good afternoon, counsel.
Barbara? Excuse me. Barbara.
Oh, good, good.
Have you got a minute?
I have a question about this new will.
I'm sorry, I don't think I can help you.
It came as big a surprise to me
as it did everyone else.
I think you can handle this one.
If Kathy is convicted,
who inherits the money?
Well, in this case, the old will stands.
Now, let me guess.
Lacey gets a fortune,
and your firm gets the prestige of
being executors, plus millions in fees.
One thing I learned from my father:
Be damn sure about your facts
before you make an accusation
as serious as that.
Mr. Matlock.
Well, I'll say it again,
you're very good.
- And very angry.
- Thank you.
I tried very hard for that first part--
- What's the matter?
- Oh, no.
My car.
There's no spare.
But that's okay.
There's no jack, either.
I suppose I could call the auto club.
Yeah.
It'll take hours before they get here.
Oh, yeah.
Do you have a spare or a jack?
- Yeah.
- Well, what about it?
What about it?
What happened
to Southern hospitality?
Gallantry.
Or did that die at Appomattox?
Okay. There you go.
Now, you ought to rotate your tyres
more often.
- Oh, I'll try to remember that.
- Yeah, you see that left-front there?
- The tread's almost gone.
- Oh, I hadn't noticed.
- Yeah.
- Can I buy you a drink?
Oh, I just--
- I wonder if we should.
- School night, right?
Well, we go someplace cosy
for a nice drink,
and then someplace to eat,
and one thing leads to another,
and the next thing you know,
we're discussing the case.
So?
Well, it's just that I believe she is
and you believe she isn't.
- What?
- Innocent.
- I know you do. You're supposed to.
- Well, I know.
And I know that you think
some of the circumstantials
point the other way.
Oh, I believe
what the evidence says.
And I believe her, see?
I believe that this man did love her
and did plan to marry,
and that's why the ring and the will.
No, I don't think so.
- You don't think that happened?
- No, of course not.
I mean, I think it can happen
with people, but--
Yeah. I do too, I do too.
Though it probably shouldn't
about half the time.
- Yeah.
- Right.
- Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
Well, there you go.
I knew we'd wind up
talking about the case.
Right.
Well.
- There you--
- Thank you.
Now-- Okay, rotate.
- Oh, okay. Goodbye.
- Bye.
Put that one back...
Well, hello, my baby
Hello, my honey
Hello, my ragtime gal
Send me a kiss by--
- How's it going, partner?
- Hey, all right.
Charlene.
Think I should get a new suit?
No.
You think I look okay
in this old thing?
Great.
How's the lady DA look?
Fine.
Why?
When your father starts going through
a second adolescence,
you can add two and two.
Oh, there's nothing going on.
Oh, Daddy, it's all right.
But there's nothing going on.
I mean, it's just professional.
I'm sure it is.
But you've been singing
''Hello, My Baby'' for three days now.
We interrupt
this high-level legal conference
to bring you some good news.
In fact, this falls under the heading
of superior news.
And not a second too soon.
I hope you're not toying
with an old man's hopes.
I ran a records check
on Kathy's husband, and it's true.
He doesn't work
at that garage anymore.
He owns the garage.
He just bought it. He paid cash for it.
- Where'd he get the money?
- Maybe somebody paid him off.
I guess whoever killed Peter St. John
has some money.
- A whole lot of money.
- A whole lot.
Mr. Dawson,
what did you say to your wife
when you telephoned her
the night of the murder?
That I needed to talk to her
just one more time.
If I could make her
understand how I felt,
she wouldn't go through the divorce.
And did she agree to see you?
- Yes.
- Tell the jury what happened.
- She came over to our apartment--
- Excuse me.
What time was that?
- A little after 8.
- Go on.
She came in,
I asked to take her coat.
She said she wasn't staying.
She said she could say everything
she had to tell me in five minutes.
I tried to ask her to change her mind,
to give me a second chance.
She just laughed at me.
She said, ''I've got a new life now,
I don't want anything to do
with the old one.''
And then she left.
Mr. Dawson,
how long was your wife
in your apartment?
Like I said, maybe ten minutes.
By 8:30, she was gone.
Did she say anything to you
about the deceased, Mr. St. John?
Please answer the question.
- I don't wanna hurt her.
- Mr. Dawson, answer the question.
She said she was about to
get her hands on some real money,
and that she never wants
to see me again.
No further questions.
Say Kathy told you
she was gonna get her hands
on a lot of money, did she?
Yeah.
You're a pretty fortunate young man
yourself, aren't you?
- I don't understand.
- A couple of weeks ago,
you worked in a garage, didn't you?
- Yeah.
- As a mechanic.
- Yes.
- You don't do that anymore, do you?
- No.
- Now you own the garage, don't you?
Don't look at
the assistant district attorney.
She can't help you on this one.
Don't you?
- Yes.
- How'd you pay for it?
- Cash.
- Tell the court how much cash.
A hundred and eighty-five
thousand dollars.
Tell the court
where you got $1 85,000.
Look, I love my wife,
and I guess she's still my wife--
Just answer the question.
Kathy gave me the money.
- Kathy gave you $1 85,000?
- No.
She gave me a necklace.
A diamond necklace.
She said it was mine
as long as I didn't make any problem
with the divorce.
She said she didn't care
about giving it to me
because there was plenty more
where that came from.
Eric's lying.
I never gave him anything.
I never took anything out of the safe
but the ring.
So somebody else
had the combination to the safe.
Lacey,
or Barbara, or the housekeeper.
And whoever took that necklace
and gave it to Eric
killed Mr. St. John.
That can wait, Chris. I want you
to help Marcus with the silver, please.
I just wanted you to know
we'll be upstairs
about another half hour.
Wouldn't it be simpler
if you just moved in?
Ben, where are you?
Oh, dear.
Right here, Tyler,
helping out in the laundry room.
Whenever you feel like
doing a little work,
Charlene and I are waiting.
Ben?
I'll be right with you.
- All set, Tyler?
- I'm ready.
- Ready, Charlene?
- All set.
All right, now, give me a few seconds
to get there, then let her rip.
Now, just once,
I'd like to see him play the decedent.
Oh, help me! Oh, I'm dying!
Somebody! Does anybody hear me?
- Tyler, that's enough. Tyler.
- Please help me.
Come here quick! I need some help!
Twenty-three seconds.
What about you?
- Well, what do you think?
- It was chilling.
Chilling. I never heard
death screams like that.
- No, I mean, what did you find out?
- A lot.
Like what?
I absolutely know she did it.
Miss St. John,
I'd like to start with a few questions
about your background,
and I'd like to assure the court
that these are most relevant.
Your father died
when you were quite young.
- Isn't that true?
- That's right.
And your mother raised
both you and your brother.
Yes, she worked as a caterer.
That's a fancy word for it, isn't it?
Actually, she was a maid.
And let me hasten to add,
there's nothing wrong
with honest work.
A woman alone
with two small children.
She worked very hard.
But still, you were ashamed of her,
weren't you?
No, never.
But years later, when your brother
started making big money,
your life changed, didn't it?
Peter was the perfect big brother.
Yes, he was extremely generous.
And so was his wife,
the former Evelyn Rutledge.
Thanks to her, you and your brother
became part of Atlanta's society.
Not just part of society,
but as they say,
- the crme de la crme.
- Objection.
I don't understand what this has to do
with her brother's murder.
I believe I can show relevancy
in a moment, Your Honour.
Overruled. Continue.
Now, your brother's wife died
4 years ago.
She was not only his wife,
but his hostess.
When she died,
you became the hostess.
That's a strong position for a wife.
Maybe even stronger for a sister.
What would have happened
to your position
if he had married Kathy Dawson?
Practically a servant in your house.
That wouldn't have concerned me.
He wouldn't have asked you
to stop being the hostess?
No more parties,
pictures in the society page?
He wouldn't have asked you
to move out?
Objection. Calls for speculation.
Everything that meant something
to you just slipping away?
- Objection.
- Sustained.
You had a bad fall off a horse
a couple of months ago,
- didn't you?
- Yeah.
And you had to wear a back brace
for a while.
I confess,
I saw it in your laundry room.
Only when I overdo
or when I get tired.
How'd your doctor treat the pain?
- Pain pills.
- Any injections?
Sometimes.
Did you ever hear of Monocane?
I really don't know.
An empty bottle of Monocane
was found in Kathy's room.
Now, the painkiller Monocane
was not prescribed for your brother,
but he received a fatal overdose
by injection.
What was Kathy doing with
a bottle of Monocane in her room?
Then I got to thinking
about the back brace, and...
You stole that bottle of Monocane
from your doctor, didn't you?
- No.
- Then used it to kill your brother.
- No, I did not.
- Objection, Your Honour.
This entire line of questioning
is totally speculative.
Sustained.
Well, let's go on to something
quite factual.
Would you say
this is an accurate representation
of the 2nd Floor
of your brother's house?
- Yes.
- And this is your brother's room here?
- Down the hall, around the corner
- in the separate wing is your room.
- Correct.
- It's quite private, isn't it?
- Yes.
In fact, when I had my associate,
Tyler Hudson,
lie down in your brother's bed
and holler he was being murdered,
I couldn't hear him in your room.
My brother
did not have to holler for me.
He had an intercom installed
in his bedroom after his accident,
and he could contact anyone
in the household with it.
Now, let me get this straight.
You didn't actually hear your brother
yell for help
- the night he was being killed.
- No.
He called for me on the intercom.
Oh, the same way he calls
the housekeeper and the butler.
Yes.
So then, you ran from your room
in the separate wing,
around the corner,
met the housekeeper,
and the two of you ran on down
to your brother's room.
Yes.
You know,
when my associate called for help,
calling into the intercom,
you know what I heard
on the intercom in your room?
Nothing. I'm not kidding.
I heard absolutely nothing.
I don't believe you.
So I checked the intercom
in your brother's room.
You know what I found?
He had disconnected the button
to your room.
- Did you know he had done that?
- That's not true.
He told you
he was gonna marry Kathy, didn't he?
- No.
- And you were furious.
You were no longer gonna be first
in your brother's life.
He never loved her.
He couldn't have.
He was an invalid,
unable to get out of bed.
That's the only way he had
to break it off with you,
was to disconnect that wire,
and that's what he did.
He cut the wire between you
and you never knew.
No, he loved me.
It wasn't just the money.
You were losing that,
but you were losing position,
and you were losing him.
You were going to be alone,
and it hurt.
It hurt so much
that you would rather see him dead
than to be left alone.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
They say waiting for a baby to come
is suspenseful.
Waiting for a jury to come in
is suspenseful, isn't it?
Well, no matter how this turns out,
I think you put on an excellent case.
- And you put on an excellent defence.
- There you go.
If the jury finds for Kathy,
I hope that--
And I'm not talking about the money,
but I hope that she can live a full life.
Well, she's a nice girl.
You know, when I was in college,
there was this boy.
I don't know why
I got thinking about him,
but I guess it's this case and love.
But his name was Garrett Steele.
And he was tall,
and he had dark brown hair
and blue eyes.
Grey-blue.
The colour of the ocean
on a cloudy day.
Yeah.
- Good-Iooking, huh?
- Oh, well, I thought he was.
I liked him so much,
I was almost afraid to look at him.
Years later--
He's a doctor now.
--I found out that he liked me too,
and I never knew that.
Oh, missed it, yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Then, of course, that happened to me.
I guess it's happened to everybody.
You know, there was this one girl,
Betty Ann Snow.
- She had hazel eyes.
- Jury's in, Ben.
We, the jury,
find the defendant not guilty.
Having been found not guilty,
the defendant is ordered released.
Court is adjourned.
Thank you.
You were wonderful.
Not too bad, I guess.
Congratulations.
Hold the elevator.
Thanks.
Wanna have that dinner?
I'll buy.
www.tvsubtitles.net